Andrew Shay

Highland, MI 48356 - (734) 904-0160 - 1996ashay@gmail.com - linkedin.com/in/andrewdshay/ - github.com/adshay18

Summary

Software Engineering professional with experience in object-oriented programming, developing, testing, debugging, and UI design. Proven ability to quickly learn and incorporate new technologies in the data stack.

Previous experience in data acquisition and analytics through Psychological perspective.

Education

Springboard, Software Engineering - *Certificate*

JULY 2022

Software Engineering Career Track dedicated to learning: Web Development, Software Developer Fundamentals, Modern JavaScript, and Python.

Hope College, Holland, MI - B.A. Psychology - Minor Mathematics

DECEMBER 2017

Skills

Technical – HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, DOM, Python, Flask, SQL/PostgreSQL, AJAX, Node, Express, git, Github, Terminal

Workplace - Department Coordination, Ethics, Conflict Resolution, Maintenance/Repair

Project Work

Portfolio Website [https://shay-portfolio.surge.sh]

Please visit the above portfolio website, which itself is built on React.js and deployed through the npm package, surge. There are links to project work including two capstone projects developed during coursework at Springboard. The first of which, Picl, is a site designed to let users search for, like, and pin images to boards. The second, not-bored, is a site that gives users the experience to find random tasks to alleviate boredom.

Other Experience

Quick Release - Project Analyst

JUNE 2022 - PRESENT

Found and delivered technical solutions to help clients get new products to market faster, more efficiently and more sustainably. Worked alongside client teams to understand their challenges, provide expert guidance, and follow up with the technical know-how to put that guidance into action. Supported deployments and development of technical software tools and solutions.

DoorDash - Dasher SEPTEMBER 2020 - MAY 2022

Acquired and transported food to customer homes in order to provide a great service experience; this position helped deliver aid to those who were unable to shop in public due to health concerns over COVID-19.

Early Autism Services, Troy, MI - Behavior Technician

JUNE 2018 - JULY 2019

Delivered ABA therapy to young clients diagnosed with Autism to foster conversation skills, motor skills, and develop self-help protocols. Collected and interpreted data to assist in writing detailed notes on client progress and provided information to insurance companies.

Hope College, Holland, MI - Research Assistant

JANUARY 2017 - DECEMBER 2017

Researched what contributes to a flourishing and meaningful life as part of a larger study to provide solidifying data for a researched based novel. Presented relationships of variables at research showcases, including the Midwestern Psychological Association annual conference, through APA style posters to display findings.